Guide to the Harry Randall: Fifteenth International Brigade Films and Photographs ALBA.PHOTO.011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series D: Miscellaneous, September 1937-June 1938; August 1938, 10355
  - Photo Unit #: D117 Captain Hans Amlie (l.), Captain Malcolm Dunbar, Major Robert Merriman, Colonel Stephen Fuqua (American Military Attache ) in Quinto after Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10527 (Item 11-0842)
    (Moscow Number: 5/195/1)
  - Photo Unit #: D118 Colonel Stephen Fuqua, David Doran and Captain Hans Amlie at Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10526 (Item 11-1350)
  - Photo Unit #: D119 Colonel Stephen Fuqua (l.), David Doran and Captain Hans Amlie at Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10525 (Item 11-0843)
  - Photo Unit #: D120 Colonel Stephen Fuqua reviews troops at Quinto after Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10524 (Item 11-0844)
    (Moscow Number: 5/195/11)
  - Photo Unit #: D121 Colonel Stephen Fuqua reviews troops at Quinto after Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10523 (Item 11-0845)
  - Photo Unit #: D122 15th International Brigade in shower machine at Quinto after action at Fuentes de Ebro, Oct 1937; 10522 (Item 11-1777)
    (Moscow Number: 5/181/3)
  - Photo Unit #: D123 Moving back to Quinto from Fuentes de Ebro Front, [soldiers in cart], Oct 1937; 10521 (Item 11-1781)
    (Moscow Number: 5/181/10)
  - Photo Unit #: D124 Robert Minor at Fuentes action, Nov 1937; 10520 (Item 11-0846)
  - Photo Unit #: D125 Robert Minor at Quinto during Fuentes de Ebro offensive, Nov 1937; 10519 (Item 11-0847)
    (Moscow Number: 5/188/56)
  - Photo Unit #: D126 Lieutenant Colonel Vladimir Copic, Robert Minor and [?], Nov 1937; 10518 (Item 11-0848)
    (Moscow Number: 5/177/14)
  - Photo Unit #: D127 Robert Minor in Quinto during Fuentes de Ebro, Oct 1937; 10517 (Item 11-0849)
    (Moscow Number: 5/189/12)
  - Photo Unit #: D128 Robert Minor, Fuentes de Ebro, Nov 1937; 10516 (Item 11-0850)
    (Moscow Number: 5/188/55)
  - Photo Unit #: D136 Students from Federation of University Students at 15th Brigade (Spanish Universal Federacion), Nov 1937; 10515 (Item 11-1082)
  - Photo Unit #: D139 Scene at ceremony of presentation of flags to British Battalion, [with two flag bearers], Dec 1937; 10514 (Item 11-1793)
    (Moscow Number: 5/184/4)
  - Photo Unit #: D148 General Walter examining a rifle, Dec 1937; 10513 (Item 11-1351)
  - Photo Unit #: D149 Armored train in Quinto, Oct 1937; 10512 (Item 11-0851)
  - Photo Unit #: D153 Jacques Lemare and Henri Cartier-Bresson filming at Quinto., Oct 1937; 10511 (Item 11-0261)
  - Photo Unit #: D154 Henri Cartier-Bresson in Quinto (probably in October 1937), Oct 1937; 10510 (Item 11-0852)
  - Photo Unit #: D160 Print from captured negative taken in Quinto action of Aug and Sep 1937, 10509 (Item 11-1196)
    (Moscow Number: 5/180/12)
  - Photo Unit #: D161 Meyer Levin of "Esquire" visits Lincoln-Washington Battalion at Alvares, Dec 1937; 10508 (Item 11-0853)
  - Photo Unit #: D162 Ernest Hemingway with other American visitors to 15th International Brigade, Dec 1937; 10507 (Item 11-1352)
  - Photo Unit #: D164 Ernest Hemingway, Dec 1937; 10506 (Item 11-1353)
  - Photo Unit #: D165 Ernest Hemingway with other American visitors to 15th International Brigade, Dec 1937; 10505 (Item 11-1354)
  - Photo Unit #: D166 [Men] of anti-tank [company?] reading [newspapers] from home [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], Dec 1937; 369375 (Item 11-1892)
  - Photo Unit #: D169 On the firing range, Dec 1937; 10504 (Item 11-1801)
    (Moscow Number: 5/184/13)
  - Photo Unit #: D170 Rifle range, Mondejar [men lying on ground, taking aim], Dec 1937; 10503 (Item 11-1355)
  - Photo Unit #: D184 David Doran at 24th Battalion, Taranca, Dec 1937; 10502 (Item 11-1197)
  - Photo Unit #: D188 Brigade and English Battalion officers with William Rust and Harry Pollitt [not visible] at English Battalion [crowd of troops listening], Dec 1937; 10501 (Item 11-1356)
  - Photo Unit #: D189 Harry Pollitt at English Battalion [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], Dec 1937; 369376 (Item 11-1893)
  - Photo Unit #: D192 Harry Pollitt [?] addressing English Battalion, Sep 1938; 10500 (Item 11-1756)
    (Moscow Number: 5/176/2)
  - Photo Unit #: D193 Brigade and English Battalion officers William Rust and Harry Pollitt at English Battalion, Dec 1937; 10499 (Item 11-1357)
  - Photo Unit #: D194 Brigade and English Battalion officers William Rust and Harry Pollitt at English Battalion [with group, arms raised in salute], Dec 1937; 10498 (Item 11-1358)
  - Photo Unit #: D199 Washing clothes, Dec 1937; 10497 (Item 11-1083)
  - Photo Unit #: D202 Train trip, Ambite, Alcaniz, Dec 1937; 10496 (Item 11-1084)
  - Photo Unit #: D203 Anti-air Machine Gunner on Train, Dec 1937; 10495 (Item 11-1085)
  - Photo Unit #: D204 On trip from Ambite to Alcaniz [group of men; railroad car with IB poster on it], Dec 1937; 10494 (Item 11-1359)
  - Photo Unit #: D205 Anti-Aircraft Machine-Gunners on [roof of] train, Dec 1937; 10493 (Item 11-1360)
  - Photo Unit #: D207 Trip from Ambite to Alcaniz, Dec 1937; 10492 (Item 11-1086)
  - Photo Unit #: D214 On trip from Ambite to Alcaniz, 35th Division Artillery [2 men in open freight car], Dec 1937; 10491 (Item 11-1361)
  - Photo Unit #: D215 Unloading, Dec 1937; 10490 (Item 11-1087)
  - Photo Unit #: D217 15th International Brigade picking olives, Alcaniz, Dec 1937; 10489 (Item 11-1762)
    (Moscow Number: 5/180/24)
  - Photo Unit #: D218 15th International Brigade men picking olives, Alcaniz, Dec 1937; 10488 (Item 11-0262)
  - Photo Unit #: D221 Anti-Gas section of Lincoln-Washington, Dec 1937; 10487 (Item 11-1088)
  - Photo Unit #: D222 Lieutenant Colonel Vladimir Copic addressing Lincoln-Washington and 24th Battalion Awards, Christmas, Dec 1937; 10486 (Item 11-1089)
  - Photo Unit #: D224 Trip from Ambite to Alcaniz, Dec 1937; 10485 (Item 11-0854)
  - Photo Unit #: D228 Morris Brier and Otto Reeves with Anti-war Machine-Gunner MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, Dec 1937; 10484 (Item 11-1362)
  - Photo Unit #: D229 Church, Masde las Matas where English and MacKenzie-Papineau were quartered, Dec 1937; 10483 (Item 11-1090)
  - Photo Unit #: D231 General Walter [Karol Scwierczewski] examines a rifle in 15th Brigade, Dec 1937; 10482 (Item 11-0855)
  - Photo Unit #: D232 Aragonese anarchist [Rufino Tio "Pipa"] in Alcorisa, Dec 1937; 10481 (Item 11-1091)
  - Photo Unit #: D236 David Doran, Haldane, Robert Merriman, Dec 1937; 10480 (Item 11-1363)
  - Photo Unit #: D237 Robert Merriman, [?] Haldane, Vladimir Copic, Dec 1937; 10479 (Item 11-1364)
  - Photo Unit #: D239 An American of Lincoln-Washington Battalion, Dec 1937; 10478 (Item 11-1092)
  - Photo Unit #: D240 Our trenches at Fuentes Caliente, Jan 1938; 10477 (Item 11-1093)
  - Photo Unit #: D242 Lying down to get a drink, Fuentes Caliente, Jan 1938; 10476 (Item 11-1365)
  - Photo Unit #: D244 [Soldier with machine gun] [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], [Jan 1938]; 369377 (Item 11-1894)
  - Photo Unit #: D245 Steaks, Jan 1938; 10475 (Item 11-1094)
  - Photo Unit #: D248 Interior of a home near Teruel, Jan 1938; 10474 (Item 11-1095)
  - Photo Unit #: D251 Sign outside Teruel, "Alto A Teruel", Jan 1938; 10473 (Item 11-1366)
  - Photo Unit #: D252 Reading and rest room for men of our outfit, Feb 1938; 10472 (Item 11-0856)
  - Photo Unit #: D258 MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion and civilian fiesta at Tivisa, [seated children], May 1938; 10471 (Item 11-1839)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/32)
  - Photo Unit #: D260 After Teruel [4 soldiers sitting against wall, one reading a newspaper], Feb 1938; 10470 (Item 11-1367)
  - Photo Unit #: D261 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10469 (Item 11-0857)
  - Photo Unit #: D266 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10468 (Item 11-0858)
  - Photo Unit #: D267 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10467 (Item 11-0859)
  - Photo Unit #: D270 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10466 (Item 11-0860)
  - Photo Unit #: D271 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10465 (Item 11-0861)
  - Photo Unit #: D273 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10464 (Item 11-0862)
  - Photo Unit #: D274 After Teruel, Feb 1938; 10463 (Item 11-0863)
  - Photo Unit #: D275 Ambulance, after Teruel, Feb 1938; 10462 (Item 11-0864)
  - Photo Unit #: D278 Dental Wagon at work, "Doc" [Jack] Klein, Feb 1938; 10461 (Item 11-0865)
  - Photo Unit #: D279 Ambulance, "From the Workers of West Virginia", Feb 1938; 10460 (Item 11-1368)
  - Photo Unit #: D280 Ambulance labeled "The West Virginian No. 2"] and drivers [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], Feb 1938; 369386 (Item 11-1895)
  - Photo Unit #: D281 Kitchen [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], Feb 1938; 369378 (Item 11-1896)
  - Photo Unit #: D285 Recruits at Alcorisa, Feb 1938; 10459 (Item 11-1369)
  - Photo Unit #: D289 Earl Browder addressing MacKenzie-Papineau at station near Teruel, Feb 1938; 10458 (Item 11-1096)
  - Photo Unit #: D292 Print from captured negative, Feb 1938; 10457 (Item 11-1097)
  - Photo Unit #: D295 Men of 59th Battalion who received awards at Christmas time, Jan 1938; 10456 (Item 11-1826)
  - Photo Unit #: D296 Football game, 15th Brigade U.S. Alcorisa, Juventud Socialista Unificada, Feb 1938; 10455 (Item 11-1098)
  - Photo Unit #: D300 Spectators at football game [including women], Feb 1938; 10454 (Item 11-1370)
  - Photo Unit #: D303 Refugio near Lincoln-Washington Battalion kitchen, Feb 1938; 10453 (Item 11-1099)
  - Photo Unit #: D304 Cedrilla, Feb 1938; 10452 (Item 11-1100)
  - Photo Unit #: D305 Group of Spanish soldiers, on stone steps, Feb 1938; 10450 (Item 11-1371)
  - Photo Unit #: D306 Festival, 15th International Brigade, Popular Front, Feb 1938; 10449 (Item 11-0866)
  - Photo Unit #: D314 Shelters made by comrades of Company 2, 59th Battalion, Mar 1938; 10448 (Item 11-1101)
  - Photo Unit #: D317 15th Brigade Estado Mayor [Headquarters] outside Hijar at retreat, Mar 1938; 10447 (Item 11-1102)
  - Photo Unit #: D323 Meeting of Political Commissars of 15th Brigade with Luigi Gallo, Mar 1938; 10446 (Item 11-1372)
    (Moscow Number: 5/189/22)
  - Photo Unit #: D324 Peasant weaving, Mar 1938; 10445 (Item 11-1103)
  - Photo Unit #: D325 Outside Hijar, Mar 1938; 10444 (Item 11-1104)
  - Photo Unit #: D326 Group, Genie of 61st Brigade waiting to go to front. Also point of road control. [group at checkpoint, some on ground with piles of gear], Mar 1938; 10443 (Item 11-1373)
  - Photo Unit #: D329 Farmlands, Hijar, Mar 1938; 10442 (Item 11-1374)
  - Photo Unit #: D331 Repairing clothing, MacKenzie-Papineau, Mar 1938; 10441 (Item 11-1105)
  - Photo Unit #: D335 Women and children at Letur, Mar 1937; 10440 (Item 11-1375)
  - Photo Unit #: D337 River Letux, Mar 1938; 10439 (Item 11-1106)
  - Photo Unit #: D346 Water wheel, MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, Ebro Front, May 1938; 10438 (Item 11-0867)
  - Photo Unit #: D369 [Soldiers, group], Jan 1938; 10437 (Item 11-1107)
  - Photo Unit #: D370 [Soldiers, group], Jan 1938; 10436 (Item 11-1108)
  - Photo Unit #: D371 [Soldiers, talking], Jan 1938; 10435 (Item 11-1109)
  - Photo Unit #: D372 [Three soldiers], Jan 1938; 10434 (Item 11-1110)
  - Photo Unit #: D373 [Three soldiers], Jan 1938; 10433 (Item 11-1111)
  - Photo Unit #: D377 [At the front], Jan 1938; 10432 (Item 11-1112)
  - Photo Unit #: D380 [Officers addressing the troops (?)], Jan 1938; 10431 (Item 11-1113)
  - Photo Unit #: D381 [Woman addressing the troops (?)], Jan 1938; 10430 (Item 11-1114)
  - Photo Unit #: D387 [Soldiers, group], Jan 1938; 10429 (Item 11-1115)
  - Photo Unit #: D390 [Soldiers in a bunker], Jan 1938; 10428 (Item 11-1116)
  - Photo Unit #: D393 [Soldiers with auto], Jan 1938; 10427 (Item 11-1376)
  - Photo Unit #: D394 [Soldiers with auto], Jan 1938; 10426 (Item 11-1377)
  - Photo Unit #: D395 [3 soldiers, 3 women], Jan 1938; 10425 (Item 11-1378)
  - Photo Unit #: D396 [Group of soldiers with one woman], Jan 1938; 10424 (Item 11-1379)
  - Photo Unit #: D397 [Crowd, a few soldiers, mostly men and women civilians; car in background], Jan 1938; 10423 (Item 11-1380)
  - Photo Unit #: D398 [Group of soldiers, same locale as D394, 395, 397], Jan 1938; 10422 (Item 11-1381)
  - Photo Unit #: D399 [2 soldiers with bulletin board], May 1938; 10421 (Item 11-1382)
  - Photo Unit #: D400 [3 soldiers], May 1938; 10420 (Item 11-1383)
  - Photo Unit #: D401 International Brigade Conference, May 1938; 10419 (Item 11-1384)
  - Photo Unit #: D402 [Officers addressing the troops], Jan 1938; 10418 (Item 11-1117)
  - Photo Unit #: D403 [Officers addressing the troops], Jan 1938; 10417 (Item 11-1118)
  - Photo Unit #: D405 [Soldiers, group], Jan 1938; 10416 (Item 11-1119)
  - Photo Unit #: D409 [Officers addressing the troops], Jan 1938; 10415 (Item 11-1120)
  - Photo Unit #: D410 International Brigade Conference, May 1938; 10414 (Item 11-1385)
  - Photo Unit #: D417 [Spaniards (?)], May 1938; 10413 (Item 11-1121)
  - Photo Unit #: D422 [Officers addressing the troops], May 1938; 10412 (Item 11-1122)
  - Photo Unit #: D424 15th International Brigade [meeting?], May 1938; 10411 (Item 11-1760)
    (Moscow Number: 5/177/44)
  - Photo Unit #: D427 [Officers addressing the troops], May 1938; 10410 (Item 11-1123)
  - Photo Unit #: D429 [Soldiers marching], May 1938; 10409 (Item 11-1124)
  - Photo Unit #: D434 [At attention, staff meeting (?)], May 1938; 10408 (Item 11-1125)
  - Photo Unit #: D438 15th International Brigade on watch, [marching on road with flag], May 1938; 10407 (Item 11-1761)
    (Moscow Number: 5/180/1)
  - Photo Unit #: D439 [Soldiers, marching], May 1938; 10406 (Item 11-1126)
  - Photo Unit #: D441 [Officers addressing the troops], May 1938; 10405 (Item 11-1127)
  - Photo Unit #: D442 [Officers addressing the troops], May 1938; 10404 (Item 11-1128)
  - Photo Unit #: D443 [Soldiers, marching], May 1938; 10403 (Item 11-1129)
  - Photo Unit #: D445 [At attention, staff meeting (?)], Jun 1938; 10402 (Item 11-1130)
  - Photo Unit #: D446 [Soldiers, marching], May 1938; 10401 (Item 11-1131)
  - Photo Unit #: D447 [At attention, staff meeting (?)], May 1938; 10400 (Item 11-1132)
  - Photo Unit #: D449 Square in Alcorisa, Jan 1938; 10399 (Item 11-1133)
  - Photo Unit #: D451 Fountain in Alcorisa, Jan 1938; 10398 (Item 11-0868)
  - Photo Unit #: D452 Fountain in Alcorisa, Jan 1938; 10397 (Item 11-0869)
  - Photo Unit #: D454 Showers, Ebro Front, Apr 1938; 10396 (Item 11-1386)
  - Photo Unit #: D459 Ambulance from Teachers Union and American Student Union, Murray Nemeroff driving, May 1938; 10395 (Item 11-0870)
  - Photo Unit #: D460 Ambulance from Teachers Union and American Student Union, Murray Nemeroff driving, May 1938; 10394 (Item 11-0871)
  - Photo Unit #: D462 Campesinos at dance in Valls, May 1938; 10393 (Item 11-1134)
  - Photo Unit #: D469 Practicing infiltration: Cabos School, May 1938; 10392 (Item 11-1135)
  - Photo Unit #: D472 15th International Brigade School for Cabos, May 1938; 10391 (Item 11-1136)
  - Photo Unit #: D475 Hospital at Valls, May 1938; 10390 (Item 11-1137)
  - Photo Unit #: D485 British Battalion listening to John Gollan [not visible], Ulldemolins, Jan 1938; 10389 (Item 11-1387)
  - Photo Unit #: D486 British Battalion listening to John Gollan, Ulldemolins, May 1938; 10388 (Item 11-1138)
  - Photo Unit #: D495 Funeral of Lieutenant William Digges, Mollerusa, May 1938; 10387 (Item 11-1139)
  - Photo Unit #: D496 Funeral of Lieutenant William Digges, Mollerusa [soldiers carrying coffin], Jan 1938; 10386 (Item 11-1388)
  - Photo Unit #: D497 Funeral of Lieutenant William Digges, Mollerusa, May 1938; 10385 (Item 11-1140)
  - Photo Unit #: D498 Funeral of Lieutenant William Digges, Mollerusa, May 1938; 10384 (Item 11-1141)
  - Photo Unit #: D499 Funeral of Lieutenant William Digges, Mollerusa [soldiers at graveside], May 1938; 10383 (Item 11-1389)
  - Photo Unit #: D506 Activist Congress, Marca, Jun 1938; 10382 (Item 11-1142)
  - Photo Unit #: D509 Some delegates, Activist Congress, Marca, Jun 1938; 10381 (Item 11-1143)
  - Photo Unit #: D511 Louis Bortz (Bradely) [?] mail censor, Barcelona, May 1938; 10380 (Item 11-1144)
  - Photo Unit #: D513 Fascists taken prisoner (150) Belchite, Sep 1938; 10379 (Item 11-1145)
  - Photo Unit #: D514 Fascists taken prisoner (150) Belchite, Sep 1938; 10378 (Item 11-1146)
  - Photo Unit #: D515 Fascists taken prisoner (150) Belchite, Sep 1938; 10377 (Item 11-1147)
  - Photo Unit #: D516 Fascists taken prisoner (150) Belchite, Sep 1938; 10376 (Item 11-1148)
  - Photo Unit #: D518 Refugees from Belchite, Sep 1938; 10375 (Item 11-1149)
    (Moscow Number: 5/191/102)
  - Photo Unit #: D523 15th International Brigade on train ride, Valencia, Dec 1937; 10374 (Item 11-1150)
  - Photo Unit #: D525 Cabo School, Ebro Front, May 1938; 10373 (Item 11-1151)
  - Photo Unit #: D527 Fiesta, MacKenzie-Papineau and civilians at Tivisa, Edward Cecil Smith, David Doran, Frank Rogers, May 13, 1938; 10372 (Item 11-1390)
  - Photo Unit #: D545 School for Commissars, Ebro Front, May 1938; 10371 (Item 11-1152)
  - Photo Unit #: D546 MacKenzie-Papineau, Hijar, Mar 1938; 10370 (Item 11-1391)
  - Photo Unit #: D550 Swim and change of clothes for 15th International Brigade, May 1938; 10369 (Item 11-1392)
    (Moscow Number: 5/191/93)
  - Photo Unit #: D556 Football game, 13th and 15th International Brigades, Tarraga, May 1938; 10368 (Item 11-1153)
    (Moscow Number: 5/192/1)
  - Photo Unit #: D558 Football game, 13th and 15th International Brigades, Tarraga, May 1938; 10367 (Item 11-1154)
  - Photo Unit #: D562 British Battalion machine-gun company, Tarraga, May 1938; 10366 (Item 11-1816)
    (Moscow Number: 5/185/16)
  - Photo Unit #: D565 Soldiers at Activists Congress, Marca, Jun 1938; 10365 (Item 11-1155)
  - Photo Unit #: D569 Sanidad [Health], lunch time, Marca, Jun 1938; 10364 (Item 11-1156)
  - Photo Unit #: D571 Trade Union Delegation at MacKenzie-Papineau, in the vineyards, Jun 1938; 10363 (Item 11-1393)
  - Photo Unit #: D577 Recruit group building fortifications, Marca [copy negative; transferred from the Victor Berch Papers, ALBA 080], Jun 1938; 369379 (Item 11-1897)
  - Photo Unit #: D578 Lincoln-Washington boys with peasants tending vines, Marca, Jun 1938; 10362 (Item 11-1394)
  - Photo Unit #: D579 MacKenzie-Papineau group marching to vineyards, Jun 1938; 10361 (Item 11-1157)
  - Photo Unit #: D582 MacKenzie-Papineau group working in vineyards, Marca, Jun 1938; 10360 (Item 11-1198)
  - Photo Unit #: D585 Joseph Brandt of Lincoln-Washington Battalion reading news, Jun 1938; 10359 (Item 11-0872)
  - Photo Unit #: D587 Hospital, wounded soldier reading in bed, undated; 10358 (Item 11-1395)
  - Photo Unit #: D599 Auto Park, Alcover, Aug 1938; 10357 (Item 11-1396)
  - Photo Unit #: D600 Volunteer for Liberty, Alcover, Aug 1938; 10356 (Item 11-1158)
- Series E: Miscellaneous, 1938-01-1939-09; 9594
  Series IIE: Miscellaneous, January 1938 - September 1938. Many of the 761 images in this series capture the final battles of the International Brigades. The most arresting shots are those taken at the crossing of the Ebro in July 1938. In an article that appeared in the Volunteer for Liberty in September 1938, Randall described the Photo Unit's activities and the photographic record they created during the Ebro Offensive:
  "In the period of reorganization and training that preceded our crossing of the Ebro, we were busy snapping pictures of training schools, delegations, fiestas, activities, meetings, classes, congresses, etc. Then the moment came when we prepared to attack. Ben Katine took a fine set of pictures of our comrades crossing the river in boats and rafts of the building of the first footbridge and the first groups of our soldiers to walk across it to the west bank of the Ebro, ours once more. We went ahead with our troops as we advanced, and later made pictures of the ruins of towns bombed by the Fascist planes."
  This series also includes pictures of peasants working in the fields of Marca; the presentation of a flag by Juventud Socialista Unificada (Unified Socialist Youth of the Spanish Communist Party); and the evacuation of wounded in Gandesa.
  - Photo Unit #: E0001 Lincoln Brigade troops marching to North Pole, Teruel Sector [snowy landscape with distant figures], Jan 1938; 10354 (Item 11-1397)
  - Photo Unit #: E0002 Company 2, Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10353 (Item 11-1398)
  - Photo Unit #: E0003 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10352 (Item 11-1399)
  - Photo Unit #: E0005 Officers of 15th International Brigade and others at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10351 (Item 11-1400)
  - Photo Unit #: E0006 Alvin Cohen, action scene, Company 1, Lincoln-Washington Battalion North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10350 (Item 11-1401)
  - Photo Unit #: E0007 Action Scene, Company 2, Lincoln-Washington, North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10349 (Item 11-0064)
  - Photo Unit #: E0008 Spain 1938, scene in Terrega, May 1938; 10348 (Item 11-1402)
  - Photo Unit #: E0011 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10347 (Item 11-1403)
  - Photo Unit #: E0012 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10346 (Item 11-1404)
  - Photo Unit #: E0013 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10345 (Item 11-1405)
  - Photo Unit #: E0014 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10344 (Item 11-1406)
  - Photo Unit #: E0015 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10343 (Item 11-1407)
  - Photo Unit #: E0016 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10342 (Item 11-0065)
  - Photo Unit #: E0017 Lincoln-Washington digging Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10341 (Item 11-1408)
  - Photo Unit #: E0019 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10340 (Item 11-1409)
  - Photo Unit #: E0020 Lincoln-Washington Battalion marching to Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10339 (Item 11-0066)
  - Photo Unit #: E0022 Lincoln-Washington Battalion trench at North Pole, Teruel Sector, Jan 1938; 10338 (Item 11-1410)
  - Photo Unit #: E0023 Captain Leonard Lamb and Captain Milton Wolff of Lincoln-Washington Battalion at North Pole, Jan 1938; 10337 (Item 11-1411)
  - Photo Unit #: E0024 Action Scene, Company 1, Lincoln-Washington Battalion at North Pole, Teruel, Jan 1938; 10336 (Item 11-1412)
  - Photo Unit #: E0025 Action Scene, Company 1, Lincoln-Washington Battalion at North Pole, Teruel, Jan 1938; 10335 (Item 11-1413)
  - Photo Unit #: E0026 Machine-Gun Company 1, Lincoln-Washington Battalion at North Pole, Teruel, Jan 1938; 10334 (Item 11-1414)
  - Photo Unit #: E0031 Truck pulling anti-tank gun at Cuevas Labradas, Jan 1938; 10333 (Item 11-1415)
  - Photo Unit #: E0033 Brigade officers near Teruel, Jan 1938; 10332 (Item 11-1416)
  - Photo Unit #: E0035 Brigade officers near Teruel, Jan 1938; 10331 (Item 11-1417)
  - Photo Unit #: E0036 Dugout at Brigade Estado Mayor [Headquarters] near Teruel, Jan 1938; 10330 (Item 11-1418)
  - Photo Unit #: E0039 WalterCallion, chauffeur and Auto Park mechanic near Teruel, Jan 1938; 10329 (Item 11-0067)
  - Photo Unit #: E0041 Dr. Edward Barsky and Dr. Weiss [?] at Hyar, Dec 1937; 10328 (Item 11-0068)
  - Photo Unit #: E0046 Robert Minor, Major Robert Merriman and Earl Browder at Valverde, Feb 1938; 10327 (Item 11-1419)
  - Photo Unit #: E0047 Major Robert Merriman and Earl Browder at Valverde, Feb 1938; 10326 (Item 11-0069)
  - Photo Unit #: E0049 [Soldiers at train tracks], undated; 10325 (Item 11-0070)
  - Photo Unit #: E0050 Crowd entertained by accordion, Feb 1938; 10324 (Item 11-1420)
  - Photo Unit #: E0052 [Two soldiers], undated; 10323 (Item 11-1421)